JACOB FAIRWEATHER

Phone: (903) 456-7964 | Email: jacobfairweather91@gmail.com | Austin, TX LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacob-fairweather/ GitHub: https://github.com/jakefair97 Portfolio: https://jakefair97.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer leveraging a background in customer service who is able to anticipate client needs and meet their demands both in customer-facing roles as well as internally. Experienced in process improvement and leading initiatives to determine issues in company process' and proposing solutions to address them.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+

Libraries/Frameworks: jQuery, Bootstrap

Tools: RESTful APIs, Git, Node.js

PROJECTS

Poké-Search https://github.com/tpesti96/Project-01-group-4 https://tpesti96.github.io/Project-01-group-4/

- My team and I built a web application that displayed information about a pokemon as well as a GIF image based on a user's search utilizing RESTful APIs
- Core responsibilities: integrating the Tenor GIF API into the webpage
- JavaScript, Semantic UI library, PokèAPI, Tenor GIF API

EXPERIENCE

Bakery Service Team Member Whole Foods Market

Feb 2023 – Present

Austin, TX

Provide customer service to shoppers while producing quality baked goods that meet our standards in a fast-paced grocery store.

Key Accomplishments:

- Assist an average of 20 customers each day by answering questions and assisting shoppers with their needs
- Manage, produce, and inventory over 200 units of product each day
- Communicate with team members across multiple departments to assist customers and complete daily tasks in a timely manner

Sales Associate Hollywood Feed

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

Austin, TX

Assisted customers by providing recommendations of products to boost the well-being of their pets and increased productivity by efficiently stocking new supplies as well as optimizing delivery routes.

Key Accomplishments:

- Attended trainings to learn about products that we carried to recommend the best products for our customers' pets needs
- Optimized delivery routes to decrease drive times by 15%
- Generated spreadsheets detailing our sales goals for the month

Store Manager Birds Barbershop

Nov 2021 - May 2022 Austin, TX

Managed a fast-paced hair salon by providing calendar and utility support to the stylists and customer support to clients.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed an average of nine calendars each day, ensuring that each stylist received an equal amount of clientele
- Provided customer service in person, over the phone, and through SMS messaging
- Generated a report to address concerns about lost revenue due to missed appointments and proposed a solution that would reduce the loss by 15%

Administrative Assistant

Feb 2020 - Oct 2021

Jackson School of Geosciences, UT Austin

Austin, TX

Provided administrative support to the advising suite, including calendaring, front desk management, and event planning.

Key Accomplishments:

- Served as the first point of contact for anyone seeking to speak to the advising department
- Lead the planning and execution of a virtual commencement ceremony for 85 graduating students during the COVID-19 pandemic

Work Control Specialist (Temp) Lock and Key Services, UT Austin

Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

Austin, TX

Provided support to the work control team by assisting faculty, staff, and students with key requests, organizing key authorization forms, and keeping the office space organized. Key Accomplishments:

- Organized and filed an average of 200 key authorization forms everyday
- Identified and re-filed over 400 unidentified key returns

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development: UT Austin, Austin, TX July 2023

Bachelor of Arts, Sociology: The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX May 2019